Guide to the collection of Scott Helmes Artworks
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Scott Helmes artworks
2009-2010
AOB 127
Yale University Arts Library
0.25
(1 binder)
The collection contains a selection of works by visual poet Scott Helmes, who is an artist active in St. Paul, Minnesota.
Helmes, Scott, 1945-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the artist, 2009-2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Scott Helmes is an artist and visual poet, active in St. Paul, Minnesota.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains a selection of artworks by visual poet Scott Helmes, including examples of editioned prints from his Haiku series.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Works, 2009-2010. II. Correspondence, 2010.
Visual poetry; Helmes, Scott, 1945-
- Works, 2009-2010; Series I; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Four Poems from Estuary Blues by Jesse Freeman, 2009; 1 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Poster Poem No. One. Printed in an edition of fifty by Philip Gallo at the Hermetic Press in collaboration with Stamp Pad Press.
  - Haibun on 28 II 09, 2009; 1 (Box 1)
  - Haiku #47, 2010; 1 (Box 1)
    Edition of 52. Printed by Philip Gallo at the Hermetic Press.
  - Haiku #49, undated; 1 (Box 1)
    No. 6 in an edition of 30.
  - Haiku #53, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Haiku #81, undated; 1 (Box 1)
    Edition of 59.
  - Movement 2 VII 09, 2009; 1 (Box 1)
    "'Movement' [is] a concrete poem by Scott Helmes, printed by Scott Helmes at the Hamilton Wood Type and Print Museum in July, 2009. In an edition of 18, on varying sizes and paper types resulting in different appearances of the word, depending on the inking and paper." No. 14/18.
- Correspondence, 2010; Series II
  - Typescript letter signed from Scott Helmes to Jae Rossman, March 29, 2010 (2 pages, plus envelope)., 3 items (Box 1)